Norman Gentieu Collection Relating to Eastwood Lane
Norman Gentieu Collection Relating to Eastwood Lane
1913-1981
Gentieu, Norman, 1914-2009.
.5 linear ft.
Collection of the American author and historian related to his interest in the composer Eastwood Lane. The collection includes copies of correspondence with Modena Scovill Lane (Eastwood Lane's widow), published copies of several Eastwood Lane compositions for piano and research material used by Gentieu to write about Eastwood Lane.
5061266
Biographical History
Norman Gentieu (1914-2009) was an American author and historian from Philadelphia whose interest in twentieth century jazz led him to research and publish articles on Eastwood Lane.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Norman Gentieu Collection Relating to Eastwood Lane consists of Correspondence-subject files, Printed material and Research material.
Correspondence-subject files include letters to Norman Gentieu from Modena Scovill Lane, the widow of Eastwood Lane, and a small number of letters from Eastwood Lane.
Printed material consists of one piece of artwork, two books, one by Modena Scovill, a concert program and several copies of published sheet music by Eastwood Lane.
Research material consists of photocopies of correspondence from the originals which are in the Eastwood Lane Papers.
Location of Originals
Originals of the photocopied correspondence may be found in the Eastwood Lane Papers.Originals are here and here and here.
Arrangement of the Collection
All material is arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
See also the
Eastwood Lane Papers
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Music; New York State; Lane, Eastwood, 1879-1951.; Gentieu, Norman, 1914-2009.; Scovill, Modena.; Books.; Correspondence.; Sheet music.; Author
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Originally accessioned as part of the Eastwood lane Papers, gift of Mary Meloscia and Thomas S. Pletcher, 2013.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Belwyn Mills Publishing Corp., 1976 (Box 1)
  - Cranberry Lake, undated (Box 1)
  - Lane, Modena Scovill, 1951; 1952,; 1967,; 1973-1976,; 1977-1981; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Lane, Sidney Eastwood, 1950 (Box 1)
  - New York University, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Unidentified, 1977 (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Artwork
    - Crapsody by Willy Pogany, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Books
    - Keyboard Harmony Book II by Modena Scovill, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Two Centuries of American Musical Composition, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Concert programs
    - Carnegie Hall Reinald Werrenrath song recital, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Sheet music
    - Abélard and Héloise for piano solo by Eastwood Lane, 1933 (Box 1)
    - Adirondack Sketches: A suite for piano by Eastwood Lane, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Caravan from China for piano solo by Eastwood Lane, 1933 (Box 1)
    - Five American Dances for piano by Eastwood Lane, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Fourth of July by Eastwood Lane, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Girl on Tiptoe for piano solo by Eastwood Lane, 1933 (Box 1)
    - Here are ladies five piano pieces by Eastwood Lane, 1944 (Box 1)
    - In Sleepy Hollow for piano by Eastwood Lane, 1913 (Box 1)
    - The Little Fisherman words by Dana Burnet, music by Eastwood Lane, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Persimmon Pucker for piano solo by Eastwood Lane, 1926 (Box 1)
    - Sea Burial for piano solo by Eastwood Lane, 1925 (Box 1)
    - Sold Down the River by Eastwood Lane, 1928 (Box 1)
- Research material
  - Photocopies of correspondence between Eastwood Lane and Modena Scovill, undated; originals are in the Eastwood Lane Papers.; 2 folders (Box 1)